早上好
Good morning.
现在是美丽的库母茨郡的上午八点
It's 8:00 in wonderful Coombs County,
本地警方再一次拒绝确认或否认…
where once again state police have refused to confirm or deny
当地居民接连目睹的神秘“空中之光”的发现
more of those mysterious "lights in the sky" sightings by local residents.
以下是“漫游空中”电台记者对目击者…
Roving air reporters spoke with Miss Josie Floss,
乔西福洛斯女士所作的采访
who made just such a sighting.
我亲眼看见那些亮光
I've seen those lights with my own eyes.
当我报警的时候，他们告诉我说那是沼气在燃烧
And when I called the police, they told me it was swamp gas.
简直是扯淡！库母茨郡哪儿来的沼气？
Bullshit! Ain't no swamps in Coombs County!
我跟你说，非法的外来生物将借助这光…
I tell you, with them illegal aliens...
又是个好天气啊！
Gonna be a sparkling day.
好天气！
Sparkling.
简直要把我逼疯了！克莱拉！
Makes me crazy! Clara!
克莱拉！
Clara!
我这儿又没电了，克莱拉！
My electric's gone out again, Clara!
我要错过我的肥皂剧了！
I'm gonna miss my soaps!
行了，你别嚷嚷了！
Oh, stop your yakking.
比尔？
Bill?
比尔，艾尔维拉那儿又停电了
Bill, Elvira's blacked out again.
帮我传个话
Pass the word.
过得愉快，宝贝儿！
Have a nice day, honey.
好的  谢谢你，布恩夫人  你也一样
Okay, thanks, Mrs. Boone. You, too.
艾尔维拉那儿又没电了
Elvira's got no electric.
她看不成她的肥皂剧了  她要气炸了！
She can't see her soaps, she'll hyperventilate.
是个野餐的好日子，玛姬！
Great day for a picnic, Maggie!
我真是等不及了，布恩先生  祝你逮到条大鱼哦！
Can't wait, Mr. Boone. Catch yourself a big one!
尽力而为
If I can!
奶奶，你的午餐做好放在冰箱里了
Granny, I fixed your lunch and put it in the fridge.
玩得尽兴哦，孩子！
Have fun, child.
你确定你一个人能行吗？
Sure you're gonna be okay?
我没事的，宝贝儿
I'll be fine, dear.
你管你去吧  再见！
Now you just run along. Bye!
嗨，罗根夫人
Hi, Mrs. Rogan.
嗨，玛姬
Hi, Maggie.
野餐盒找到了吗？
Did you find that picnic basket yet?
在客厅里呢
It's in the living room.
哦，谢谢  亚里克斯呢？
Oh, thanks. Where's Alex?
他还能去哪儿呢？
Where else?
对了
Right.
路易斯
Louis.
早上好，太空之子路易斯
Good morning, space-son Louis.
地球人啊！
Earthling.
路易斯
Louis!
珍妮！
Jane!
艾尔维拉那儿又没电了
Elvira's electric is out again,
她要是看不到她的肥皂剧又要发疯了！
and she's gonna get hyper if she can't see her soaps!
奶奶，告诉艾尔维拉，亚里克斯会赶在肥皂剧开始前…
Granny, tell Elvira that Alex will be over
把线路修好的
to patch her electric in time for the soaps.
我会告诉她的，珍妮  艾尔维拉！
I'll tell her, Jane. Elvira!
-路易斯！ -艾尔维拉！
- Louis! - Elvira!
路易斯！
Louis!
去把亚里克斯叫过来
Go tell Alex that I need him.
当心着点，外星人！
Beware, aliens.
路易斯 罗根——宇宙军学员…
Louis Rogan, the cosmic cadet,
太空复仇者——前来收拾你！
the space avenger, is on your case.
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter!
你已被星空联盟录取，誓死保卫边境
You have been recruited by the Star League to defend the Frontier
抗击约和柯-旦舰队的入侵
against Yur and the Ko-Dan Armada.
作好准备！即将发射升空！
Get ready. Prepare for blastoff!
好了，开始吧！
Okay. Let's go.
准备进行目标射击训练，星空战士！
Prepare for target light practice, Starfighter.
亚里克斯，妈妈在找你！
Mom's looking for you, Alex.
打那儿！打那儿！
Right there! Right there!
瞄准
Aim.
等他们经过中点时…
They're all through the center.
就射击，知道了吗？
Shoot them, okay?
现在自下向上射击
Now from the bottom up, okay.
那里有一个
There's one right over there.
行，打得不错  那里！
Okay, doing good. Right up there.
把你的头挪开好吧，路易斯？
Move your head, will you, Louis?
啊，对不起
Uh, sorry.
玛姬！
Maggie!
嘿，大伙儿！你们好吗？
Hey, you guys. Hi. How you doing?
快点儿，亚里克斯  他们到了！
Come on, Alex. They're here!
玛姬——拖车场女王！
Maggie, queen of the trailer park!
星空战士亚里克斯 罗根请求…
Well, Starfighter Alex Rogan requests permission
转由我弟弟路易斯来驾驶，长官！
to turn the bridge over to my little brother, Louis, sir!
哈哈，你们这群白痴死定了！
Okay, you dorks are dead.
你被打败了  请再投入二十五美分
You are defeated. 25 cents more, please.
哦，破玩意儿！
Oh, crapola.
-罗根，快点儿！ -嘿，亚里克斯，日子过得可好？
- Rogan, come on. - Hey, Alex, how you doing, man?
-稍等一下  -我们快走吧，伙计
- Just a second. - Big Al. Let's do it, buddy!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
快啊，亚里克斯  赶紧！
Come on, Alex. Hurry up!
亚里克斯，你到底去不去？
Alex, did it come yet?
噢，不  我不想去了
Uh, no. I don't think so.
这次又怎么了，罗根？
What's it this time, Rogan?
你要打算参军了？
You joining the Foreign Legion?
是，长官，乡亲们  都来看看啊！
Yes, sir, folks. Step right up.
见见我们的冒险家亚里克斯 罗根的…
Meet boy adventurer Alex Rogan
走向失败的世界环游
on the last leg of his worldwide tour to nowhere.
很好笑哦，布雷克
Funny, Blake.
你们以为我在这儿就是看你们显摆汽车…
You guys think I'm gonna hang out here, watch you shine your pickup,
每个星期六晚上在酒店喝得烂醉，还吐得一塌糊涂…
go to the drive-in, get drunk and throw up every Saturday night,
还跟在别人屁股后面上大学？
go to City College like everybody else?
得了吧，伙计  我要用生命成就一番大业
Forget it, man. I'm doing something with my life.
-哦！较真儿先生！  -亚里克斯！
- Mr. Serioso. - Alex!
什么事？
Yeah?
宝贝儿，艾尔维拉家又停电了
Honey, Elvira's electric is out.
哦，妈，那要花掉我一整天
Oh, Ma, that's gonna take all day.
我还打算去银湖玩呢
I was going to Silver Lake.
宝贝儿，我知道  真的很抱歉  我要做中饭和晚饭
Honey, I know. I'm sorry. I'm working lunch and dinner.
我一天都要在镇上
I'm gonna be in town all day!
哦，好吧  算了，妈，我去修吧
Oh, all right. Okay, Ma. I'll do it.
谢谢你了，宝贝儿！
Thanks, honey.
我们要迟到了
We're gonna be late.
那…你们…
Look. You...
你们去吧  我不去了
You'd just better go ahead without me.
不，亚里克斯，我留下
No. Alex, I'll stay.
不用，没关系的  修好得要花上一段时间
No. That's okay. This'll take a while.
我修好了来找你们
I'll catch up with you later.
亚里克斯…
Alex...
拜拜，罗根！
Bye-bye, Rogan!
等会儿见啦，老兄！
See you, dude!
亚里克斯，快来帮忙啊！
Alex, come help me!
嘿，亚里克斯，能帮我一下吗？
Hey, Alex. Could you give me a hand here?
谢谢啦，亚里克斯！
Thanks, Alex!
我们今晚该做点什么呢？
What should we do tonight?
谁知道啊
I don't know.
打牌怎么样？
How about cards?
嘿，是个好主意！
Hey, that's a good idea.
但是我们昨晚刚打过啊
But we played cards last night.
那…
Well...
太太们今晚要进城跳舞
The missus wants to go into town tonight and go dancing.
鱼在水里使老大劲地向下扯
The fish were really biting down there at the stream.
今天钓得真尽兴
It was pleasant fishing today.
是啊  明天依然是个好天气
Yup. It's gonna be pleasant tomorrow, too.
根据农历来看，今年夏天可是个好夏天啊
Gonna be a pleasant summer according to Farmer's Almanac.
是啊  我最爱农历了
Yeah. I love the Farmer's Almanac.
我研究了好多年了
I've been reading it for years.
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取，誓死保卫边境
You have been recruited by the Star League
抗击约和柯-旦舰队的入侵
to defend the Frontier against Yur and the Ko-Dan Armada.
是啊，是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
作好准备！即将发射升空！
Get ready. Prepare for blastoff.
准备进行目标射击训练，星空战士！
Prepare for target light practice, Starfighter.
哦，嗨，亚里克斯
Oh, hi, Alex.
嘿，Otis
Hey, Otis.
你的玛姬呢？
Where's your Maggie?
问得好
Good question.
我想…在外面玩得尽兴着呢
Out having a good time, I guess.
哦，你从来也没玩得尽兴过
Oh. And you never have a good time.
对不对？
Is that it?
是啊  我就喜欢帮人维修用了三十年的保险丝箱
Oh, sure. I love patching 30-year-old fuse panels
还喜欢帮人通马桶
and plunging people's toilets.
Otis，我从来也没有机会…
Otis, I never even get a chance
在这儿玩得尽兴过
to have a good time around here.
事情总是会改变的  永远都这样
Things change. Always do.
你会有机会的
You'll get your chance.
重要的是，当它来临时…
lmportant thing is, when it comes,
你要用双手紧紧地抓住它
you got to grab it with both hands and hold on tight.
敌军在三、六、七区，快速接近中
Enemy squadrons in Sectors 3, 6, 7 closing fast.
谢谢你，杰克
Thanks, Jack.
别客气
You're welcome.
-晚安，玛姬  -晚安
Good night, Maggie. Good night.
我还以为你会去湖边找我呢
Thought you were gonna meet me at the lake.
发生了什么事？
What happened?
相同的事总是发生  我没办法脱身
Same thing that always happens. I couldn't get away.
其他人呢？
Where's everybody else?
哦，他们去看电影了
Oh, they went to a movie.
老杰克 布雷克碰巧和你同路，啊？
Old Jack Blake just happened to be going your way, huh?
敌军在三区出现
Enemy squadron in Sector 3.
他说他正好顺路回家
He said it was on his way home.
布雷克住在镇的那头
Blake lives on the other side of town.
拜托，亚里克斯
Come on, Alex.
我就想回到你身边
I wanted to get back to you.
可以了吧？
Okay?
打得不错，星空战士！你真行！
Good show, Starfighter! Way to go.
亚里克斯，看啊！
Alex, look!
哦，天啊！有多少？九十万？
Oh, my God. What is that? 900,000!
九十万！你要破纪录了！
900,000! You gonna bust the record!
嘿！嘿！大家，听好了！
Hey! Hey! Listen up, everybody!
亚里克斯破纪录了！
Alex is going for the record!
纪录？
Record?
去…去看看
Take... Take a hand.
打中了！哦，他就要打中那架了！
Got them! Oh, he's gonna get that one!
你行的！
You can do it!
Otis？
Otis?
Otis，你在嚷嚷什么？发生什么事了？
Otis, what are you yelling about? What's wrong?
快来啊！快！
Come on! Come on!
他就要破纪录了！
He's going to bust the record!
快！快！
Hurry! Hurry!
大家都退后！别挤到他！
Everyone get back! Don't crowd him!
我说了，快退后！
I said, get back!
亚里克斯，你以前从来没打出过这个成绩！
Alex, you never got this far before!
加油，亚里克斯！
Go, Alex!
真争气！
Good boy!
柯-旦指挥舰进入射程
Ko-Dan command ship entering kill zone.
指挥舰！
Command ship!
哦，是指挥舰！
Oh, command ship!
指挥舰是什么？
What's a command ship?
你行的，亚里克斯！你绝对行！
You can do it, Alex! You can do it!
再来一次！加油啊！就是它！
One more now. Come on! That's the one!
要打的就是它！
That's the one we want!
好啊！太棒了！
Yeah! Yeah!
晚安  你真行，亚里克斯！
Good night. Way to go, Alex!
晚安，孩子们
Good night, kids.
亚里克斯，你真够可以的
Alex, you're something else.
你真棒，孩子
You're wonderful, boy.
谢谢
Thank you.
我说的话准能成真
If I said it once, I said it a thousand times.
那孩子见得了世面
That boy's gonna go places.
他真够聪明的
That's one smart boy.
晚安，亚里克斯
Good night, Alex.
“晚安，亚里克斯”？等等
"Good night, Alex"? Wait a second.
玛姬？玛姬？
Maggie? Maggie?
等一下  你要去哪里？
Hold on a second. Where are you going?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我突然才发觉…
Well, I guess it just hit me.
你真的要离开这儿了，对吗？
You really are leaving here, aren't you?
当然，我当然要走  我们一起离开这里
Of course, I'm leaving. We're both gonna leave here.
-我们一起，亚里克斯？  -是啊
Both of us, Alex? Yeah.
我们对此已经谈过了
We talked about this.
等我入了学，我就会找个地方…
When I get to school, I'm gonna find a place
然后回来接你
and I'm gonna come back and get you.
那…奶奶怎么办？
Well, what about Granny?
奶奶？
Granny?
其实是你自己害怕离开这个拖车场吧？
Truth is, you're scared of leaving this trailer park.
我才不怕离开这个拖车场呢，亚里克斯
I'm not scared of leaving this trailer park, Alex.
嘿，听好
Hey. Listen.
无论发生什么，我都和你在一起，对吧？
Whatever happens, it's you and me forever, right?
对吧？
Right?
我真的很爱你，亚里克斯
I love you so much, Alex.
我也永远爱你，玛姬
I'll always love you, Maggs.
真恶心
Diarrhea.
玛姬！玛姬！
Maggie! Maggie!
亚里克斯，我要回去了  晚安
Alex, I got to go in. Good night.
-晚安  -晚安
Good night. Good night.
总有一天他们会说：“一切就是从这开始的”
Someday they're gonna say, "This is where it all began."
什么意思？
What?
妈，我终于打破了“星空战士”的纪录
Mom, I finally broke the Starfighter record.
哦，那太好了，宝贝儿
Oh, that's nice, dear.
好？简直是令人惊叹！
Nice? It's stupendous!
亚里克斯
Uh, Alex,
布兰纳先生知道你想尽快看到这个…
Mr. Brenner knew that you'd want to see this as soon as possible,
所以他把这个带到了餐馆…
so he brought it by the diner and...
我很兴奋，所以就把它打开了
Well, I was so excited, I opened it.
哦，没关系  里面说什么？
Oh, that's okay. What is it?
是关于你的贷款
It's about your loan.
你仍然可以和你的朋友一起上大学
You can still go to City College with your friends.
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取，誓死保卫边境
You have been recruited by the Star League to defend the Frontier.
你已被星空联盟录取…
You have been recruited...
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取…
You have been recruited...
作好准备！即将发射升空！
Get ready. Prepare for blastoff.
你好  请问，孩子…
Hello. Excuse me, son.
商店已经关门了，先生
Store's closed, mister.
我不是来买香烟或者泡泡糖的，孩子
I'm not here for cigarettes or bubble gum, my boy.
你能不能告诉我…
Can you tell me the name of the person
打破那边那个游戏纪录的人的名字？
who broke the record on that game over there?
我在哪里可以找到他？
Where I might find him?
是亚里克斯 罗根  他现在就在你面前
Alex Rogan. You're looking at him.
亚里克斯 罗根  啊哈！
Alex Rogan. Aha!
-你是谁？  -森特利是我的名字
Who are you? Centauri's the name.
那个游戏是我发明的  它就是我来这儿的原因
I invented Starfighter, which is why I'm here.
-真的？  -当然
It is? It is.
我们得谈谈一件极重要的事
We have to talk about a matter of utmost importance.
请进入我的办公室
Step into my office.
就是它  进来吧
That's it. Come on now.
没什么好怕的
Nothing to be afraid of.
哦，对了  和我的助手贝塔打个招呼
Oh, yes. Say hello to my assistant, Beta.
你好
Howdy.
嗷！
Ow!
我必须就你的精彩表现恭喜你，我的孩子
I must congratulate you on your virtuoso performance, my boy.
你给森特利留下了深刻的印象
Centauri is impressed.
我见过有人来，也见过有人去…
I've seen them come and I've seen them go.
但是你是最棒的，我的孩子  漂亮！
But you're the best, my boy. Dazzling.
比其他人好十万八千里
Light years ahead of the competition.
这就是为什么森特利要来这儿
Which is why Centauri is here.
他有点事来找你
He's got a little proposition for you.
你有兴趣吗？
Are you interested?
我想是吧
I guess.
嘿！
Hey!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
听着
Listen.
森特利想要给你一个惊喜
Centauri wants to keep it for a surprise.
相信我，你会喜欢它的  一定会的！
Trust me. Oh, you're gonna love it. Love it!
好笑的是，这一切都是出于一个错误
The amusing thing about this, it's all a big mistake.
那个游戏…
That particular Starfighter game
应该被运往维加斯的
was supposed to be delivered to Vegas,
而不是你们那个在野草和虫子堆里的…
not some flea-speck trailer park
芝麻大小的拖车场
in the middle of tumbleweeds and tarantulas.
所以，一定是宿命，命运——误打误撞地…
So, it must be fate, destiny, blind chance,
甚至可以说是运气——把我们带到一起
luck, even, that brings us together.
有首诗说得好：“往事如烟”
And as the poet says, "The rest is history."
你要去哪儿？为什么要带我去？
Where are you going? Where are you taking me?
我告诉过你了，我要给你一个惊喜
I told you. I wanna save it for a surprise.
嘿，你是不是那种急着先读谜底的孩子？
Hey. Are you the kind of kid who reads the last page of a mystery first?
那些缠着魔术师追问奥秘的孩子？
Who pesters the magician to tell you his tricks?
那些悄悄溜下楼偷看圣诞礼物的孩子？
Who sneaks downstairs to peek at his Christmas presents?
不，你当然不是那样的！
No. Of course you're not!
所以我先不告诉你
That's why I'm not gonna tell you.
哦，天啊
Oh, God.
除此之外，我最喜欢惊喜了  难道你不是吗？
Besides, I just love surprises, don't you?
嘿！看好了！
Hey, look out!
-停车！  -天啊！
Stop! Oh, dear!
快踩刹车！嘿…
Hit the brakes! Hey...
在哥伦比亚星切换为星球驱动模式
Shifting into star drive at Columba Zeta.
抓紧了
Hold tight.
嘿  嘿，让我出去！
Hey. Hey, let me out of here!
应该有一个完全符合逻辑的理由来解释这一切
There's a perfectly logical explanation for all this.
嘿！等等！你要去哪儿？
Hey! Wait! Where you going?
嗨！你好  这是什么？
Hi! How are you? What is this?
听着，你会说英语吗？我…
Listen. Do you speak English? I'd...
这是很不错，可是…
This is nice but...
森特利，这里发生什么情况？
Centauri, what's going on here?
他说你能来这儿他很高兴…
He's just saying how delighted he is that you're here.
还有，如果你有什么需要能让你在这儿过得愉快…
And if there's anything he can do
给他打个电话就行
to make your stay more enjoyable, just give him a ring.
在这儿？你在说些什么？我们在哪儿？
My stay? What are you talking about? Where are we?
欢迎来到赖罗斯星，我的孩子！
Welcome to Rylos, my boy!
赖罗斯？
Rylos?
等等  你的意思是说…就像在游戏里一样？
Wait a minute. You mean... You mean like in a game?
哦，他反应很快嘛  很快，是很快
Oh, he's quick. He's quick. He's very quick.
他瞠目结舌了！再见了，亚里克斯！尽兴哦！
He's speechless. So long, Alex! Have fun!
但愿古鲁七柱的好运永远伴你左右
May the luck of the Seven Pillars of Gulu be with you at all times.
哦，总有一天这些混蛋们会感谢森特利的  相信我吧
Oh, someday these cheapskates will thank Centauri. Trust me.
六月份的到哪儿去了？
Where the hell is June?
犹兰达，小甜心！
Yolanda, baby!
嗨，玛姬
Hi, Maggs.
嗨，路易斯
Hi, Louis.
他起床了吗？
Is he up?
他嘟哝了一个晚上，没睡过
Yeah. He's been up all night moaning.
亚里克斯？
Alex?
你妈妈告诉我贷款的事了
Your mother told me about the loan.
有什么我帮得上的吗？
Is there anything I can do?
听着，如果你需要帮忙，我就在隔壁，好吧？
Listen. I'll be next door if you need anything, okay?
刚星群
Gunstars.
我一定是在做梦
I got to be dreaming.
是啊，没错
Yeah, right.
听着，这里有个大错
Listen, there's been a big mistake.
情况报告后立即
...immediately after situation report.
导航
Navigation...
欢迎来到星空战士指挥部
Welcome to Starfighter Command.
你在说英语了？
You speak English?
不，你听到的是英语  这要多亏了你的翻译装置
No. You hear English, thanks to your translator device.
赶紧，我们时间不多了
Hurry up. We haven't got much time.
部署会议马上要开始了
The briefing begins immediately.
请和其他录取者一同前往
Join the other recruits.
等等！等等！
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
等等！你说的录取者是什么意思？
Wait a minute! What are you talking about, recruits?
我简直不能相信！
I don't believe this.
注意  请注意！恩德伦大使已经到达
Attention. Attention, please. Ambassador Enduran has arrived
并将立即开始部署星空战士指挥部的人事工作
and will now address Starfighter Command personnel.
众所周知，我们绝望地探寻了很久…
As you all know, we have been on a desperate quest...
抱歉  抱歉
Excuse me. Excuse me.
…找到你们这些星空战士和领航员
...to find Starfighters and navigators.
我…我真应该把你捏得粉碎！
I should... I should crush you to gorun dust!
对不起，我是不小心的…
I'm sorry... It was an accident.
我不是要故意踩你的…
I didn't mean to step on your...
我也不知道叫它什么东西
Whatever that is.
可怕的生物
Hideous creature.
请允许我继续
If I may continue.
我们的军队已经…
Our forces have...
你别惹伯嘉地
You don't trifle with a Bogati.
他们很好战
They love to fight.
所以我们很适合打这场战争
That's why they're perfect for this war.
你是不是说了“战争”？
Did you say "war"?
没错！
But of course!
不然你认为你在这儿干什么？
Why else do you think you're here?
“你已被星空联盟录取，誓死保卫边境”
You were recruited by the Star League to defend...
“抗击约和柯-旦舰队的入侵”
"...to defend the Frontier against Xur and the Ko-Dan Armada."
很久很久以前，我们的祖先建造了这伟大的边境
Eons ago, our ancestors created our great Frontier,
它对敌人来说是一道屏障
a barrier of energy
维持着和平的宇宙体系
encircling the peaceful systems of the universe,
将潜在的灾祸拒于千里之外
and forever shutting out the scourge that lurks beyond.
大伙，由于无耻的背叛…
Fellow Rylans, because of a dark betrayal,
我们的边境即将瓦解
our Frontier will soon collapse.
所以，我们向你们——星空战士以及你们的领航员们——求助…
So we turn to you, Starfighters and your navigators.
代表着星际联盟几十亿的生命
For of all the billions of creatures in the Star League,
只有你们几个才被证明有那…
only you few were found to possess the
天赋
gift.
你，还有你…
You, and you alone,
正站在我们与黑暗势力的中间
stand between us and the black terror of the Ko-Dan.
胜利还是灭亡！
Victory or death!
胜利还是灭亡！胜利还是灭亡！
Victory or death! Victory or death!
现在，星空战士们，在你们的座位底下…
Now, Starfighters, if you will reach underneath your seats,
你们会发现一个装有一只手的包…
you will find a packet which contains one hand...
这里是限制区域，对你们…
This is a restricted area, off-limits to...
真对不起，星空战士
My apologies, Starfighter.
星际导航员兼一等兵听从您指挥，长官！
Star Navigator First Class Grig at your service, sir!
嗨，我是亚里克斯 罗根，我在家里玩这个游戏…
Hi. I'm Alex Rogan. I was playing this game back home,
后来有个人找到我…
and this guy came up to me.
其实他不是个人，他是外星人，对吧？
Only he's not a guy. He's an alien, right?
然后我坐上他的车——只不过那不是辆车——而是艘宇宙飞船
And I get into his car. Only it's not a car. It's a spaceship.
这里面有个大错误
And, there's been a big mistake.
我是不是要这样理解…
Am I to understand you're actually declining
你拒绝做一名光荣的星空战士？
the honor of becoming a Starfighter?
没错
You got it.
太不可思议了！
Extraordinary!
长久以来，所有的生物都梦想成为星空战士
For eons, all creatures have dreamt of being Starfighters.
-你从哪儿来？  -地球
Where you from? Earth.
我们其实和谁都没在打仗，只是互相在打
And we're not at war with anybody, except each other.
地球？地球可不是星际联盟的正式成员啊…
Earth? Earth isn't a formal member of the Star League,
而且只有等到它成熟以后我们才可以接近
and isn't due to be approached until it matures.
这太没规矩了
This is all highly irregular.
告诉我，是谁征用你的？
Tell me. Who recruited you?
森特利
Centauri.
他来了  就是他！
There he is. That's him!
森特利  我也许认识他
Centauri. I might have known.
又在故伎重演了，对吧，森特利？
Up to your old Excalibur tricks again, eh, Centauri?
你就不知道…
Did it ever occur to you that it is against the law
从星际联盟以外的地方征兵是非法的？
to recruit from worlds outside the Star League?
地球也受到了威胁，不是吗？
Earth's in danger, too, isn't it?
不，我可没有动用神剑测试哦
And, no, I did not use the Excalibur test.
只用了一个叫作“电子游戏”的东西
It was called a video game.
那又有什么关系呢？
What's all the brouhaha?
总之，他没有那种天赋
After all, he does have the gift!
这也许会让你很吃惊…
This may come as a bit of a shock to you,
但是，他并不想成为星空战士
but he doesn't want to be a Starfighter.
不想成为一个…你是个懦夫吗？
Doesn't want to be a... Are you a coward?
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
你什么都没告诉过我！
You didn't tell me about any of this!
还钱吧，森特利！
Return the money, Centauri!
还钱？你老糊涂了吗？
Return the money? Are you delirious?
你知道我花了多久发明那游戏…
Do you know how long it took to invent the games,
进行推广…
to merchandise them,
在圣诞节前放在店里销售？
to get them into the stores by Christmas?
这对于你来说一定不容易…
It must be terribly embarrassing for you,
我真的很同情，可是…
and I do sympathize. However...
但是我看到他战斗了！
But I saw him fight!
他可以成为有史以来最棒的星空战士！
He could be the greatest Starfighter ever!
那只是个游戏啊，森特利
That was a game, Centauri.
游戏？
A game?
你以为它只是个游戏，但它也是种考验
You may have thought it was a game, but it was also a test.
啊哈！一种考验！
Aha! A test!
它被发向宇宙，寻找那些具有天赋的人成为星空战士
Sent out across the universe to find those with the gift to be Starfighters.
所以你就在这儿了，我的孩子！
And here you are, my boy. Here you are!
没错，我是在这儿了  等着被杀！
Right! Here I am, about to be killed!
被杀…
Killed.
你该不会以为它很危险吧？
You don't seriously think it's dangerous, do you?
别傻了，相信我吧！
Don't be silly! Trust me!
祖尔！
Xur!
祖尔？
Xur?
是的，父亲，你那强大的边境现在正在削弱
Yes, Father, your mighty Frontier grows weaker by the moment.
别叫我父亲！
Do not call me father!
我没有你这个儿子！
You are no longer my son!
你已经被我遗弃，为什么还回来？
You're an outcast! Why have you returned?
为了所有赖仑星人好，我回来了
I have returned for the good of all Rylans.
带着柯-旦战舰回来？
With an armada of Ko-Dan warships behind you?
有些赖仑星人会欢迎我的，父亲
There are some Rylans who would welcome me, Father.
星球联盟的正义容不得你这邪教！
Star League justice put down your Xurian cult.
你的追随者既少又分散
Your followers are few and scattered.
星际联盟？
Star League?
只不过是个弱小世界的避难所，根本无法与我们匹敌！
A refuge for weak worlds not worthy to be our equals!
那也是由赖仑星人来作决定
That is for the Rylans to decide,
而不是由像你自己一样的一个既危险又邪恶的孩子来决定！
and not for a dangerous and evil child such as yourself.
然而，也就是这个孩子，捕获了你的主要间谍
And yet, it is this child who caught your master spy.
听我的吧，赖仑星人！
Hear me, Rylans!
当戈兰星的绿月黯然失色的时候，柯-旦的军队将会入侵
When the green moon of Galan is eclipsed, Ko-Dan Armada will invade,
就算你们强大的星空战士也救不了你们
and not even your mighty Starfighters will be able to save you.
我们走着瞧，祖尔  我们走着瞧！
We shall see, Xur. We shall see!
你仍然想走吗？
You still want to go?
想错过这里的精彩？
And miss all the excitement?
小屁孩儿
Little brat.
我发明了游戏，找到了那个孩子，带他过去…
I invent the game, find the kid, drag him up there,
他竟然不想成为星空战士
and he doesn't want to be a Starfighter.
我也算放弃了！
I give up!
控制中心，你能从停车角度复制我们的星角差吗？
Control, do you copy our star angle difference from parking angle?
δβ2-6，δγ3-5
Delta beta two at six, delta gamma three at five.
祖尔王命令我把他的权杖拿来
Emperor Xur ordered me to bring his scepter.
让他进来
Let him enter.
目标位置仍可见
Target vector remains on scope.
就像你们柯-旦王的一样，对吧，克里尔指挥长？
Just like your Ko-Dan emperor's, isn't it, Commander Kril?
想要统治，单单靠权杖是办不到的，祖尔
It takes more than a scepter to rule, Xur, even on Rylos.
你说得没错，克里尔
You're right, Kril.
单靠权杖的确办不到
It does take more than a scepter.
我们忍这个蠢货要忍多久？
How long must we endure this fool?
边境出现情况
We have a break in the Frontier.
发射流星弹！
Fire the meteor gun!
我亲爱的柯-旦朋友！惟恐我们忘记…
My dear Ko-Dan friends! Lest we forget,
是你们的王委任我担任本军的指挥
it was your own emperor who granted me command of this Armada.
因为只有我才知道通往边境的路
For only I hold the secret to the Frontier.
也只有我才知道星空战士基地
Only I know the location of the Starfighter base.
因此，只有我才有权命令开火！
And therefore, only I will give the order to fire!
请原谅我，祖尔
Forgive me, Xur.
我原谅你，克里尔指挥长
You are forgiven, Commander Kril.
流星弹…发射！
Meteor gunner...fire.
中士！
Sergeant!
三十一区有不明飞行物侵入，长官
I have an unidentified incoming object in Sector 31 , sir.
它们的目标是基地！警戒状态！
They're headed for the base! Alert!
我们受到攻击！
We are under attack!
重复一遍，我们受到攻击！
I repeat, we are under attack!
开启自动排斥枪！
Activate automatic repulser guns.
警戒状态！警戒状态！
Condition Red! Condition Red!
终于成功了！
At last, it is done!
不久，边境将瓦解…
Soon the Frontier will be down
他们也将向他们的新帝王俯首称臣！
and they will bow to their new emperor!
否则，我就用他们的灰烬抹灰天空！
Or I will darken the sky with their ashes.
指挥长，祖尔的间谍报告说…
Commander, the Xurian spy reports
有一个星空战士逃跑了
that one Starfighter has escaped.
逃跑？
Escaped?
你确定不需要我帮忙？
You sure I can't give you a hand?
你已经帮得够多的了  谢谢
You've done quite enough already. Thank you.
那…
Well...
反正也就几公里远了，我想……
It's only a few more miles from here. I guess...
我想我就走回去吧
I guess I can walk it.
后会有期！再见，森特利！
So long! Bye, Centauri!
哦，亚里克斯！
Oh, Alex!
给你！
Here!
嘿，听着  我不能拿你的礼物，森特利
Hey, listen. I can't take a present from you, Centauri.
他把我变得倾家荡产…
He reduces me to poverty again
他还认为我是给他礼物！
and he thinks I'm giving him a present.
什么世道啊？
What a world this is.
那它是什么？
What is it, then?
那是另一次机会，我的孩子！
It's a second chance, my boy!
如果你改变了主意，按下通讯按钮就可以了
If you change your mind, just tap the communo-crystals.
-你留着它吧  -亚里克斯，亚里克斯！
Keep it. Alex, Alex!
你正在背离历史  历史！
You're walking away from history. History!
哥伦布说过他想呆在家里吗？没有！
Did Chris Columbus say he wanted to stay home? No!
要是赖特兄弟认为只有鸟儿才会飞翔会怎么样呢？
What if the Wright Brothers thought that only birds should fly?
吉罗卡有没有认为尤鲁士人丑得无药可救呢？
And did Geloca think the Yulus were too ugly to save?
谁是吉罗卡？
Who's Geloca?
不管了
Never mind.
听着，森特利  我不是他们中的任何一个
Listen, Centauri. I'm not any of those guys.
我只是一个来自拖车场的孩子
I'm a kid from a trailer park.
如果你真是那样想的话，那你也就这样了！
If that's what you think, then that's all you'll ever be!
嘿，玛姬！
Hey, Maggie!
快听听，你绝不会相信的
Listen to this. You're not going to believe this.
我说过了，亚里克斯
I told you, Alex.
我和我的…你是怎么说的来着？
Me and my... How did you put it?
“奇怪的性冲动”再也不会和你说话了！
"Strange sexual urges," aren't talking to you anymore.
谁？
Who's there!
嘘！你会把路易斯吵醒的
Shh! You're gonna wake up Louis.
嘿！你看上去就和我一样！
Hey, you look like me!
当然，我是你的替身
Of course I do. I'm the beta unit.
替身是什么玩意儿？
What the hell's a beta unit?
替身是一个模拟体，一个你的完全的复制体，只是嗓门没那么大
A beta unit is a simuloid, an exact duplicate of you, only not as loud.
啊？
Huh?
我就在汽车里，不记得了？
I was in the starcar, remember?
我们握过手？
We shook hands?
很不幸的是，我成了你
I became you, unfortunately.
说白了，你就是个机器人？
Let me get this straight. You're a robot?
你说什么？
I beg your pardon.
我是一个既有艺术性，又是行业内顶尖级的替身……
I'm a state-of-the-art, top-of-the-line beta unit,
被放到这儿，当你不在的时候顶替你
put here as a courtesy replacement for while you're away.
我还真幸运啊
Lucky me.
等等，你怎么回来了？
Wait a minute. What are you doing back?
你开什么玩笑？那里在打仗！
Are you kidding? It's war up there!
哦，拯救鲸鱼却不拯救整个宇宙，啊？
Oh. Save the whales and not the universe, huh?
那你为什么不去打仗？
Well, why don't you go up there and fight?
模拟体不能打仗  这是不允许的
Simuloids can't fight. We're not allowed.
那告诉他们你就是我  假装嘛！
Well, tell them that you're me! Pretend!
安静点，亚里克斯
Be quiet, Alex.
对不起，路易斯
Sorry, Louis.
谢谢你的礼物！
Thanks for the lift!
别客气，伙计  再见！
Sure thing, buddy. See you around!
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取
You have been recruited by the Star League
誓死保卫边境…
to defend the Frontier against Yur and...
那…嘿！你对玛姬做了什么？
And, hey, what did you do to Maggie?
对她？
Do to her?
我们坐在外面，看着星空…
We're sitting outside, looking at the stars,
她把舌头伸到我耳朵里来
and she sticks her tongue in my ear.
我尖叫起来  我明天道歉总好了吧？
I screamed. I'll apologize tomorrow, okay?
你不该在这儿的！
You're not gonna be here.
你现在就得和森特利一起回去！
You're going back with Centauri right now!
怎么了，亚里克斯？
What's up, Alex?
回去睡觉，路易斯  不然我就告诉妈妈你和你那些《花花公子》的事
Back to sleep, Louis, or I'm telling Ma about your Playboys.
你把事情搞砸了，亚里克斯！
You're blowing it, Alex!
怎么回事！
What the shit?
我说了快回去睡觉，路易斯  不然我就告诉妈妈你和你那些《花花公子》的事
I said, back to sleep, Louis, or I'm telling Ma about your Playboys!
拜托，森特利
Come in, Centauri.
拜托，快回来
Come on. Get back here.
把你的仿真玩具带走
And take your Tonka toy with you.
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取，誓死保卫边境
You have been recruited by the Star League to defend the Frontier
抗击约和柯-旦舰队的入侵
against Yur and the Ko-Dan Armada.
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取…
You have been recruited by the Star League
誓死保卫边境…
to defend the Frontier against Yur...
你在哪儿？出来啊？你在哪儿？
Where are you? Come on, where are you?
森特利？
Centauri?
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter!
森特利？
Centauri?
哦，不好！
Oh, shit!
来啊，亚里克斯，别那么懦弱！
Come on, Alex. Don't be such a wimp!
森特利，当心！
Centauri, look out!
怎么回事…
What the...
肮脏、恶臭的生物
Foul stench. Dirty creatures.
好好看看，亚里克斯
Get a good look, Alex.
我敢打赌你以后会看见更多
You can bet your asteroids you'll be seeing more of them.
什么？
What?
这是赞多-赞
This is a Zando-Zan.
一种星际怪物，祖尔的走狗
An interstellar hitbeast, compliments of Xur.
祖尔？他为什么要跟踪我？
Xur? Why is he after me?
不知为什么，他发现你是一个星空战士
Somehow he found out you're a Starfighter.
所以，你看，亚里克斯，你得回去  你别无选择
So you see, Alex, you got to go back. You got no choice.
你要是呆在这里的话，你就变成它们的事物了
'Cause if you stay down here, you're dog food.
相信森特利，我的孩子
Trust Centauri, my boy.
因为两小时以后，这个地方将爬满十只赞多-赞s…
Because in two hours, this place will be crawling with 10 Zando-Zans
它们那木鱼脑子里只有一个目的…
with just one thought on their microscopic little minds,
杀死亚里克斯罗根
kill Alex Rogan.
Kill Alex Rogan.
他说得没错，亚里克斯
He's right, Alex.
至少在那里你还有机会在刚星里面战斗
At least up there you'll have a fighting chance in a Gunstar.
没错
Exactly.
同时，在这儿，他们会追杀替身
Meanwhile, down here, they'll be going after Beta.
-替身  -替身？
Beta. Beta?
当然  不然你以为他是干什么来的？
Of course. What do you think he's here for?
等…等等，森特利
Wait a... Wait a second here, Centauri.
亚里克斯，当心！
Alex, look out!
森特利！
Centauri!
替身，去叫医生！
Beta, get a doctor!
不，这里看不好的，因为没有巫医
No. No native cures. No witch doctors.
我没事，只是擦伤
I'm fine. Just a scratch.
面对现实吧，亚里克斯  你天生就是个星空战士
Now face it, Alex. You're a born Starfighter.
跟我去吗？
Are you with me?
好吧，我们走，森特利
Okay, let's go, Centauri.
祝你好运，亚里克斯
Good luck, Alex.
你也是，亚里克斯
You, too, Alex.
森特利呼叫星空战士指挥部
Centauri to Starfighter Command.
请回答
Come in, please.
嘿，森特利
Hey, Centauri.
所有人员注意
Attention all personnel.
星际汽车正在接近十二号停靠点
Starcar is approaching Docking Bay 12.
森特利！森特利！
Centauri! Centauri!
嘿！快踩刹车！
Hey, hit the brakes!
-格里格！嘿，格里格！  -亚里克斯！
Grig! Hey, Grig! Alex!
他们击中了森特利  他受伤了
They got Centauri. He's hurt!
他在这儿
He's right over here.
啊？你看到了？
Ah, you see?
森特利带他回来了！
Centauri brought him back!
-是的，我看见了  -别说话
Yes, I see. Don't talk.
他把我的钱拿回去了吗，亚里克斯？
Does he have my money, Alex?
我有一大笔钱给你，森特利
I have a fortune for you, Centauri.
你现在要坚持住
Now, please be still.
钱在这儿，全在这儿  一叠一叠的钱
It's here. It's all here. Piles and piles of it.
都是你的
All for you.
啊…
Ah...
终于
At last.
亚里克斯，我要你知道，能把你带回来是最幸运的事
Alex, I want you know, it was for the greatest good I brought you back.
当然，想…
Of course, it...
想要有钱也要付出点代价
It never hurts to be rich.
一路走好，老朋友
Until the next dimension, old friend.
很遗憾，亚里克斯
I'm sorry, Alex.
森特利？
Centauri?
边境任何时候都有可能瓦解
The Frontier could collapse at any moment.
亚里克斯！
Alex!
现在我的耳朵需要次手术  几乎听不到声音了
Now I need an earjob. Dying here. Dying.
亚里克斯，究竟发生了什么？
Alex, what the hell's going on?
路易斯，你正在做恶梦
Louis, you're having a terrible nightmare.
快回去睡觉
Go back to sleep.
路易斯！
Louis!
哦，不
Oh, no.
据我所知，你家里有个替身在顶替你？
Am I to understand there's a beta unit taking your place back home?
他在努力尝试
He's trying.
所以我们完全可以推断，祖尔认为你还在地球上
So it's safe to assume that Xur thinks you're still on Earth.
是啊
Yeah.
那我们在理论上可以算是有优势了
That could work to our advantage, theoretically.
啊！你现在看上去像个人了！
Ah! Now you look human!
这就是我的刚星？
Is this my Gunstar?
这只是个样品，和其他飞船有点区别
This is a prototype, different from the other ships.
她有更远的射程，更大的威力…
She has a greater range, more power,
同时，也作了轻微的装备改良
and a slight weapons modification.
当然，她还有防护层
And, of course, she's got deflective plating,
所以她经得起几次直接攻击
so she can withstand several direct hits.
我就是从这里，为飞船导航
From here, this is where I navigate the ship,
维护维生系统和推进系统
maintain life support and propulsion systems.
那我坐在哪儿？
Okay. Where do I sit?
在那边，发射席上
Way up there, in the gunnery chair.
站稳了！
Hang on!
好的
Okay.
现在，爬到发射席上
Now, climb into the gunnery chair.
我将你设置为发射状态
Now, I'm moving you into launch position.
在你前面有两个开关…
There in front of you are the two switches
可以打开显示器  现在打开它们
for your heads-up display. Turn them on.
当你和敌人交战时…
While you're engaging the enemy,
显示器会向你显示所有接近你的战舰
the screen will reflect all battle instruments towards you.
嘿，它哪儿去了？
Hey, where did it go?
它还在那儿，飘浮在氖气雾霭中
It's still there, suspended in a xenon mist.
你只要以正确的角度看就能看到
But it's only visible if you look dead ahead.
哦，看到了
Ah. Got it.
你左面的操纵杆是操纵你的座椅的
The lever on your left is the chair controller.
你可以看到，所有的枪都跟着你一起移动
As you can see, all guns will track with your every move.
右手抓紧瞄准器
Grasp the target control with your right hand.
你的手指可以操纵所有机枪——激光枪、霹雳弹…
At your fingers is the weaponry, the lasers, photon bolts...
还有粒子射线
Photon bolts and the particle beams.
等等，这和我在家玩的一样啊
Wait a minute. This is just like back home.
-这是什么？  -当心，当心…
What's this? Careful, careful,
那是死亡霸王花，最后关头才能用
that's Death Blossom, a weapon of last resort.
幸运的是，我不小心触动它的时候飞机库正在上升
Luckily, I was in here working on it when the hangar went up.
准备好了吗？所有系统，开启！
Now, are you ready? All systems, go!
点火！
Ignition!
飞机库什么时候上升？
When did the hangar go up?
我说过了，当祖尔袭击我们的时候！
I told you, when Xur attacked.
那星空战士都在哪儿？
And where were the Starfighters?
在飞机库里！
In the hangar!
你是说他们都死了？
You mean they're dead?
死是个消极的概念
Death is a primitive concept.
我宁可认为他们在另一空间与邪恶而战
I prefer to think of them as battling evil in another dimension.
在另一空间？有多少人离开了？
In another dimension? How many are left?
包括你自己？
Including yourself?
对
Yeah.
一个！
One!
一个？
One?
等等！
Hold it.
我们没有舰队，没有星空战士，连个计划也没有？
There's no fleet, no Starfighters, no plan?
-一艘飞船，你，我，没了？  -完全正确！
One ship, you, me, and that's it? Exactly!
祖尔认为你还在地球上
Xur thinks you're still on Earth.
经典战略：突袭
Classic military strategy. Surprise attack.
那简直是送死！
It'll be a slaughter!
要的就是这种精神！
That's the spirit.
不，是我去送死！
No, my slaughter.
一艘飞船对抗整个部队？
One ship against the whole Armada?
对  一架刚星对抗整个部队！
Yes. One Gunstar against the Armada.
我总是想和不可思议的敌人来一场破釜沉舟的战斗！
I've always wanted to fight a desperate battle against incredible odds.
搜索目标，亚里克斯
Target lights, Alex.
搜索目标？
Target lights?
没错  你总得在还有机会的时候…
Yes. You might want to squeeze off
多打它几个回合吧？
a few rounds while you have the chance.
发挥飞船的最大攻击力
Just work the bugs out of the system.
毕竟，这是她的处女航
After all, it is her maiden voyage.
稳住，别和座椅过不去
Steady. Don't fight the chair.
慢慢来  用枪瞄准
Take your time. Watch your gun sights.
看好目标
Lead your targets.
总之，放松就是了！
And above all, relax!
真好，我就要被杀得片甲不留…
Terrific. I'm about to get killed a million miles from nowhere
竟然还有一个蜥蜴人叫我“放松”！
with a gung-ho iguana who tells me, "Relax."
星空战士！
Interstellar!
亚里克斯！
Alex!
对不起
Sorry.
好的，来，慢慢举起来
Okay, now, come on. Ease it up.
好的
Okay.
哦，行…行了！简单
Oh, that's... That's it. Easy.
漂亮又简单
Nice and easy. Yep.
再过来点就能装好了
A little bit more and we'll get it in there, now.
亚里克斯！
Alex!
对不起  嗨，玛姬
Sorry. Hi, Maggs.
亚里克斯，你没事吧？
Alex, are you all right?
是啊，是啊  我…没事
Yeah. Yeah, I'm... I'm fine.
快点，再来一次
Come on. Try it again.
你闻到什么了吗？
Did you smell anything?
什么？
Like what?
就像…
Like a Z...
算了
Forget it.
我只是想为昨天晚上给你的巴掌道歉
I just wanted to say I'm sorry for slapping you last night.
哦，没关系，玛姬  我活该
Oh, that's okay, Maggs. I deserved it.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
要不…我们今晚去银湖弥补一下？
Well, maybe we can make it up to each other tonight at Silver Lake?
敌军将会从这里进入边境
The Armada will break through the Frontier here,
二十公里后到达赖罗斯
and reach Rylos in 20 klicks.
甲板上的空中部队将跟随母舰
Squadrons of deck fighters will precede the mother ship.
空中部队？有多少空中部队？
Squadrons? How many squadrons?
数量我倒不在乎
It isn't the number of squadrons that concerns me.
这座通信塔将指令…
It's this communication turret that sends out
发送给空中部队
the commands to the deck fighters,
这样，他们就能同时作战
which enables them to act as one during the fight.
等等，我们摧毁塔台以破坏空中部队
Wait a second. We knock out the turret to get the fighters.
但是要摧毁塔台，我们就要穿过空中部队？
But to get the turret, we have to get through the fighters.
那我们就死了
We're dead.
在到达边境前我会想出办法的
I'll have it all figured out by the time we reach the Frontier.
怎么了？
What's that?
是边境
The Frontier.
真是奇怪，运输舰…
Now, that's strange. What's a cargo ship
在边境附近干什么？
doing this close to the Frontier?
你好，这里是刚星一号
Hail. This is Gunstar One.
重复，这里是刚星一号
I repeat, this is Gunstar One.
请确认身份
Identify yourself, please.
亚里克斯，当心！
Alex, look out.
是祖尔的飞船！
A Xurian ship!
恭喜你，亚里克斯
Congratulations, Alex.
这是你第一个活体目标
This is your first live target.
活体？
Live?
五公里后进入射程  准备！
Within range in five klicks. Get ready!
我拦截了他的信号
I've blocked its beam of frequency,
所以他没办法向总部报告
so it can't report back to the Armada.
-准备好了就开火！  -格里格，等等！
Fire when ready! Grig, wait!
我们不能在洞穴里跟丢了，亚里克斯！开火！
We mustn't lose them in these caves, Alex! Fire!
开火，亚里克斯！
Shoot, Alex!
开火！
Shoot!
你成功了！
You did it!
我成功了？是你成功了！
I did it? You did it!
你差点让我送了命！
You almost got me killed!
我最诚意的道歉，亚里克斯
My deepest apologies, Alex.
我原本打算让你经历了枪林弹雨以后…
I had hoped that by putting you in the thick of battle,
一个伟大的星空战士即将诞生
a great Starfighter would emerge.
但是，唉  也许你本来就不是这块料
But, alas. Perhaps there was never one within you to begin with.
我载你回家吧
I shall take you home.
在那儿，你仍可以过上很长一段时间的安稳日子…
You still may live a long and fruitful life back there.
直到柯-旦打到地球
That is, until the Ko-Dan reach Earth.
但到了那个时候…
But then again...
嘿，布雷克！让那破音响再响一点啊！
Hey, yo, Blake! Make that sucker blast, man!
没问题，伙计！
You got it, dude! All right!
布雷克回来是拿他的裤子的对吧？
So Blake comes back in to grab his pants, right?
看到她奶奶，说…
Sees her old lady, and says,
“希望这不会让我星期二晚上没饭吃”
"I hope this doesn't rule out dinner on Tuesday night."
你真搞笑！
That's my man!
亚里克斯，你没事吧？
Alex, are you okay?
啊？
Hmm?
对啊，没事  怎么了？
Yeah, sure. Why?
我不知道，你老是走神
I don't know. You're just acting spaced out.
这…这很不像你啊
You're... You're not yourself.
如果你是我，你现在会怎么办？
Well, if you were me, what would you be doing right now?
首先呢，我会先好好享受生活
Well, for one thing, I'd be trying to enjoy myself.
靠在车上，开开玩笑，大笑
Leaning back. Kidding around. Laughing.
大笑？
Laughing?
这只是个开始，亚里克斯
Well, it's a start, Alex.
大笑
Laughing.
好地方  让我想起我的家
Nice place. Reminds me of home.
这能让你想家？
This reminds you of home?
哦，是啊
Oh, yes.
我和我的妻子和六千个孩子住在地下
I live below ground with my wifeoid and 6,000 little Griglings.
至少，在祖尔把他们变成努力之前
At least, until Xur turns them into slaves.
你们这个物种住在哪儿？
Where does your kind live?
哦，基本上都住在房子里
Oh, uh, houses, mostly.
也就是地上的洞穴  看看这个
That's caves above ground. See, here.
这是我全家
Here's my family.
看，这是…
See, that's...
这是我父母，这是我弟弟，路易斯，这是玛姬
That's my folks and my brother, Louis, and that's Maggie.
我们住在移动的家里
Uh, we live in a mobile home.
就是会去各种地方的洞穴
That's a cave that goes places.
只是我们从来没去过别的地方
Only we never went anyplace.
一个从来不去别处的移动洞穴  有意思
A mobile cave that never went anywhere. Fascinating.
是啊，但是我们在拖车场附近也有底下的洞穴
Yeah, but we have below-ground caves near the trailer parks.
我和我弟弟路易斯过去常常在里面玩捉迷藏…
Me and my brother, Louis, used to play hide-and-seek in them.
捉迷藏
Hide-and-seek.
捉迷藏是什么，亚里克斯？
What is it, Alex?
我在想，也许我们可以躲在这里…
Well, I was just thinking, maybe we could hide here,
等敌军经过的时候，从后方攻击他们的塔台
let the Armada pass by, and then hit the turret from behind.
然后，我们就以突袭的方式打败他们
Then we might take them by surprise.
你的策略也许真能奏效
Your plan might really have worked.
只可惜没有星空战士来执行它了
What a pity there are no Starfighters left to carry it out.
是啊，是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
一个祖尔的基地！
A Xurian base!
正前方还有两个  快速靠近中！
Two more dead ahead! Closing fast!
前往地球的航线已准备完毕
Earth course is logged into navigational beams.
格里格？
Grig?
什么事，亚里克斯？
What is it, Alex?
也许真的只剩下一个星空战士了
Maybe there is a Starfighter left.
啊！
Ow!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我现在是不是该把我的舌头伸到你耳朵里？
Should I put my tongue in your ear now?
算了，亚里克斯
Don't bother, Alex.
我只是…
Well, it's just...
我只是不习惯这种事…
I'm kind of new at these gland games.
你在说些什么啊？
What are you talking about?
就好像你是从外太空来的，亚里克斯！
It's like you're a million miles away, Alex!
喂，喂，喂，等等啊，宝贝儿
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait. Darling.
宝贝儿，原谅我吧
Darling, forgive me.
“宝贝儿，原谅我吧”
"Darling, forgive me."
拜托！
Come on!
你是我的茱丽叶，我的维纳斯
You're my Juliet. My Venus.
“你是我的茱丽叶，我的维纳斯”
"You're my Juliet. My Venus."
亚里克斯！
Alex!
其他女孩儿对我来说都毫无意义
All the other girls meant nothing to me.
我爱的是你啊  你，你
It was you, you, you.
住口，跟我说点脏的
Shut up and talk dirty to me.
“其他女孩儿对我来说都毫无意义  我爱的是你啊  你，你”
"The other girls meant nothing to me. It was you, you..."
我要跟你说点脏的吗？
Should I talk dirty to you now?
够了
That does it.
哦，天啊  好的，我放弃了
Oh, God. All right. I give up.
我不是亚里克斯罗根
I'm not Alex Rogan.
什么？
What?
我只是个替身
I'm a beta unit.
我是亚里克斯的复制品
I'm an exact duplicate of Alex.
他在那儿拯救全宇宙…
He's up there saving the universe,
我在这儿做敌军的诱饵
while I'm down here for target practice.
看到了吧？
See?
亚里克斯！或者不管你是谁，等等，等等
Alex! Or whatever you are. Wait. Wait.
你在干什么？让我走
What are you do... Let me go.
如果那个赞多-赞向总部报告…
If that Zando-Zan reports back
说我不是亚里克斯，亚里克斯就有危险了
that I'm not Alex, Alex is in big trouble!
-你呆在这儿  -不，我不要
You're staying here. No, I'm not.
我哪儿都不要呆直到我弄清楚真相
I'm not staying anywhere until I find out what's going on!
嘿，我的卡车！嘿，嘿，回来！
Hey, my truck! Hey, hey, come back!
有一点点擦坏，你就死定了，罗根！
Scratch that paint, and you're dead, Rogan!
入侵已就绪，指挥长
Ready to invade, Commander.
入侵
Invade.
指挥长，祖尔飞船一直没有回复我们的入侵代码
Commander, the Xurian ships have not answered our invasion code.
边境瓦解了，月亮消失了…
The Frontier is down, the moon is eclipsed,
星空战士都死了  开始入侵吧！
the Starfighters are dead. lnvade!
所有空中部队，半速前进  开启能源探测器
All squadrons ahead, half speed, with energy probes on.
能源探测器  快关闭，亚里克斯  关闭
Energy probe. Shut down, Alex. Shut down.
关闭
Power off.
亚里克斯在太空中？
Alex? ln space?
-真的假的？  -真的！我不是一直在跟你说嘛
Is this for real? - Yes! That's what I'm trying to tell you!
全是真的！
It's all for real!
那别说话了，开车啊！
Well, then, don't talk. Drive!
克里尔指挥长，紧急频率收到信号
Commander Kril, we're getting a signal on the alert frequency.
接收
Acknowledge.
到了  好的
There it is. All right.
等我接近发射器以后你就跳，知道了吗？
Now, when I give the signal, we're gonna jump! Okay?
-“跳”是什么意思？  -我们用车撞掉它
What do you mean, "Jump"? We're gonna ram him.
什么？
What?
灭绝特使六号有一则消息
Extermination Emissary Zeta 6, one message.
准备好了吗？跳！
Ready? Jump!
亚里克斯！
Alex!
“最后的星空战士…”
"The last Starfighter..."
你欠我一个人情，亚里克斯
You owe me one, Alex.
亚里克斯！
Alex!
通讯中断，指挥长
Transmission pulsars have stopped, Commander.
最后的星空战士…
The last Starfighter...
已死亡！
Is dead!
最后的星空战士已死亡！
The last Starfighter is dead!
我们是无可阻挡的了！全速前进！
Nothing can stop us now. Ahead full.
前往赖罗斯！
To Rylos!
指挥舰！
The command ship!
那儿！塔台在最后面
There! The turret at the far end!
我看见了
I see it.
祝你好运，星空战士
Good luck, Starfighter.
谢谢你所做的一切，格里格
Thanks, Grig. For everything.
我爱你，亚里克斯罗根
I love you, Alex Rogan.
六
Six.
显示器，开启
Heads-up display. Check.
五
Five.
激光枪，开启
Lasers. Check.
-四  -粒子枪，开启
Four. Particle beam. Check.
-三  -霹雳弹，开启
Three. Proton bolts. Check.
-二  -座椅控制，开启
Two. Chair control. Check.
一
One.
来吧
Let's do it.
跟踪警报
Tracking alert.
不明飞船  到底是什么？
Unidentified craft. What is it?
等等
Wait.
刚星！
Gunstar!
最后的星空战士不是死了吗？
So, the last Starfighter is dead?
我受够了  抓起来！
This has gone far enough. Seize him!
你们敢！我是赖罗斯的帝王！
How dare you? I am the Emperor of Rylos!
我，只有我，才能指挥这…
I and I alone command this entire op...
放开我！我命令你！
Release me! I command you!
你会付出生命的代价的！
You will pay for this with your lives!
全面开火！
All guns fire!
在那儿，塔台！
There it is, the turret!
亚里克斯，就现在！
Alex, now!
好！
Yeah!
击中了！
Got it!
快，亚里克斯！开火！
Hurry, Alex! Fire!
敌军积聚已经到达了赖罗斯！
The Armada's almost to Rylos!
逃生通道开启
Escape pod activated.
Escape pod ignition.
我们的感应器探测不到刚星了
The Gunstar is gone from our sensors.
向指挥部发出警报
Alert wing commanders.
通信塔台已被摧毁
Communication turret is destroyed.
所有的通信雷达系统都瘫痪了，指挥部
All communication radar systems are out, Wing Commander.
成视觉攻击队列
Proceed with a visual attack formation.
维生系统良好  弹药装备量满
Life support good. Ammo packs at peak.
我认为我们要使用死亡霸王花了
I think we've got to use Death Blossom.
记住，死亡霸王花只能在近距离…
Remember, Death Blossom delivers
给目标以重击
only one massive volley at close range.
理论上是这样的
Theoretically.
“理论上”是什么意思？
What do you mean, "Theoretically"?
毕竟，死亡霸王花从来没被测试过
After all, D.B. has never been tested.
它也许会让飞船超负荷，而毁了飞船
It might overload the systems. Blow up the ship.
你还在担心什么，格里格？
What are you worried about, Grig?
理论上，我们已经死了
Theoretically, we should already be dead.
打开死亡霸王花踏板，开启
Open Death Blossom petals. Switch is on.
没进入射程千万别发动死亡霸王花
Do not trigger D.B. until we're within range.
先用激光攻击，直到我收到信号
Just use your lasers until I give the signal.
记得要…
Remember to lead...
我被星际联盟录取…
I've been recruited by the Star League
防御边境
to defend the Frontier.
准备好了吗？
Now, are you ready?
到时候了  我们开始吧
This is it. Here we go.
冲啊！
Charge!
右面！
On your right!
左面！
Your left!
闪躲！
Evade!
能量储备不足！我们需要时间充电！
Power packs are low! We need time to recharge!
激光能量耗尽
Laser power draining!
格里格，我的武器都用完了  使用霸王花吗？
Grig, my weapons are gone! Should I do it?
慢着，慢着
Easy, easy.
等到他们都在霸王花的射程内
Wait till they're all in Death Blossom range!
发射！
Fire!
我们成功了！
We did it.
是的，我们真的成功了，对吧？
Yes, we actually did, didn't we?
是指挥舰！
The command ship!
指挥长，我们的枪已损坏
Commander, our guns are out.
维修小组正在维修
Damage control is repairing them.
还要什么枪！急速前进！
Forget the guns! Ramming speed!
格里格，我们需要能量！
Grig, we need power!
死亡霸王花用尽了所有的能量
Death Blossom's drained all power.
我正在尽力，我要运行能量激增模式！
I'm working on it. I'm trying to run boost.
我们剩下的只是维生系统的能量
All we have left is life support power!
格里格！
Grig!
好了！
All right!
可以开火了  我们有能量了  开火！开火！
Weapons on! We have them now! Fire. Fire!
估损报告
Damage report!
导航系统瘫痪，转向系统瘫痪
Guidance system out. Auxiliary steering out.
撤退！
Divert!
转向系统无响应
She won't answer the helm!
我们被锁定在月球的重力轨道上
We're locked into the moon's gravitational pull!
我们要怎么办？
What do we do?
只有死路一条
We die.
代表星际联盟和所有的赖罗斯公民…
On behalf of the Star League and all citizens of Rylos,
我祝贺你光荣凯旋
I congratulate you on your dazzling victory.
-谢谢你  -谢谢
Thank you. Thanks.
但是，你知道，边境已经瓦解…
But as you know, the Frontier is down,
祖尔也逃跑了  危险依然存在
Xur escaped, and there is still danger.
所以，我在想，你是不是愿意呆在这儿…
So I was wondering if you wouldn't be willing to stay on,
重建星际联盟？
and rebuild the Starfighter Legion.
等等
Wait a minute.
重建星际联盟？
Rebuild the Legion?
没错
Yes.
当然，你也会有一位老朋友来帮忙
Of course, you'd have the help of an old friend.
老朋友？谁？
An old friend? Who?
森特利！我以为你死了！
Centauri! I thought you were dead!
我死了，还错过精彩的战事？哦，不！
Me die and miss all the excitement? Oh, no.
我只是进入休眠状态好让我的身体自行恢复
I was merely dormant while my body repaired itself.
我就废话少说了
Now, I won't bore you with details.
一句话：你在赖罗斯星，我的孩子
Suffice it to say, you're on Rylos, my boy.
别想着人类了
Stop thinking human.
这是第一课
That's lesson number one.
现在，第二课，你在这里远近闻名
Now, lesson number two, you've got a good thing going here.
保持微笑，别扫兴
Keep smiling. Don't blow it.
第三课，总是相信森特利
Lesson number three, always trust Centauri.
亚里克斯，他们多爱你！
Alex, they love you!
你看，整个赖罗斯星就在你下面
You see, all Rylos is behind you.
你得留下 ，亚里克斯！
You've got to stay, Alex!
你会留下的，对吧？
You will stay, won't you?
当然，他会留下的
Of course, he'll stay.
这真的很令人欣慰，森特利
That's very reassuring, Centauri.
格里格，我就把这些事交给你了
Grig, I leave it in your capable hands.
我留下
I'll stay.
亚里克斯！亚里克斯！
Alex! Alex!
你好…
Greetings...
你好，星空战士
Greetings, Starfighter.
孩子，你看到亚里克斯了吗？
Bunny, have you seen Alex?
怎么会呢
Can't say that I have.
问玛姬吧，她知道他在哪儿
Well, ask Maggie. She knows where he is.
她原本和他在一起的
She was with him.
玛姬，亚里克斯呢？
Maggie, where's Alex?
我的卡车在哪儿？你的男朋友在哪儿？
Yeah, where's my truck? Where's your boyfriend?
罗根太太，关于亚里克斯，他…
Mrs. Rogan, about Alex, you see, he's...
-什么东西？发生什么了？  -我不知道
What is it? What's going on? I don't know.
哦，天啊！
Oh, my God!
太好了，我们被侵略了！
All right! We're being invaded!
玛姬
Maggie.
亚里克斯？
Alex?
嗨，玛姬
Hi, Maggs.
亚里克斯
Alex,
是你吗？
is it you?
真的是你吗？
I mean, is it really you?
看！
Look!
天啊！
My God.
真的是你！
It is you.
是亚里克斯！亚里克斯！
It's Alex! Alex!
亚里克斯，发生了什么？
Alex, what is going on here?
这是什么？
What is this thing?
这是你的太空飞船？
Is this your spaceship?
我不知道他中了什么邪了
I don't know what's gotten into him.
我真搞不懂
I don't understand that.
这太奇怪了！
It's so strange!
等等，等等  大家，安静
Wait. Hold it. Hold it, everybody.
亚里克斯，这一切是怎么回事？
Alex, what is all this?
我去了另外一个星球，妈
I've been to another planet, Ma.
另外一个星球？
Another planet?
是谁帮我修好了天线？
Who was it helped fix my antenna?
对啊，谁偷了我的卡车？
Yeah, who stole my truck?
谁切断了我家的电？
And cut my electric?
还把我的炉子弄坏了
And ruined my stove?
哦，那是…那是个替身
Oh, that was... That was a beta unit.
替身？
Beta unit?
一个机器人
A robot.
机器人？什么…
Robot? What the...
拜托！
Come on!
怪兽！
A monster!
怪兽
他给他们套上了链子
He got them chains on him.
太棒了，是外星人！
All right! It's an alien!
哦，不，等等！嘿，嘿！
Oh, no, wait! Hey, hey!
奶奶，把枪放下  你们怎么回事啊？
Granny, put away that shotgun. What's wrong with you?
这是我的朋友格里格
This is my friend Grig.
我要你们大家见见我的朋友
I want you all to meet my friend here.
你在开玩笑吧！
You got to be kidding!
格里格，这是布恩太太
Grig, this is Mrs. Boone.
你好
Hello.
这是艾尔维拉
And this is Elvira.
兴会
Delighted.
我也是  你好吗？
Me, too. How you doing?
我很好
I do well.
这是奶奶
And this is Granny.
兴会
How do you do?
这位是Otis
And this here's Otis.
很高兴见到你
A pleasure.
亚里克斯的任何朋友都…
Any friend of Alex...
这是玛姬
And this is Maggie.
非常荣幸
A very large pleasure.
嗨
Hi.
你一定是路易斯！
You must be Louis!
你的事情我如雷贯耳
I hear good things about you.
听到了吗？我很有名
Hear that, you slimes? I'm famous.
这位是我的母亲
And this is my mom.
你应该为亚里克斯骄傲，罗根太太
You should be proud of Alex, Mrs. Rogan.
你们都应该为他骄傲
You must all be proud of him.
他拯救了星际联盟以及成百上千的世界，包括地球
He saved the Star League and hundreds of worlds, including Earth.
哦，你太棒了！
Oh, for heaven's sake!
哦，天啊！
Oh, my God!
要走了，亚里克斯
Time to leave, Alex.
亚里克斯？
Alex?
我必须得走，妈
I have to, Ma.
他们那儿需要我
They need me up there.
哦，亚里克斯，我就知道有一天你要离开我们
Oh, Alex, I always knew you'd leave someday,
但我没想到会是这样
but I never expected this.
我能去吗，亚里克斯？行吗？
Gee, can I go, too, Alex? Can I?
抱歉了，小子，那里只有足够的空间…
Sorry, squirt. There's only enough room up there
给我，格里格和玛姬
for me, Grig, and Maggie.
-我？  -没错
Me? Yeah.
亚里克斯，我可不认为我能…
Alex, I don't think I can...
什么？过来，过来
What? Come here. Come here.
你认为我还会回来吗？
Why else do you think I came back?
那…我们不是说了要永远在一起的吗？
Well... Didn't we say we'd always be together?
是啊，可是我是指在这里或者城里
Well, yeah, I mean, together here or in the city.
但是…但是，在那儿，亚里克斯…
But... But up there, Alex...
玛姬，你必须得来  你看，我不知道…
Maggs, you got to come. You see, I'm not...
我不知道我什么时候才回来
I don't know when I'm gonna be back.
你不明白吗？这，就是我们最大的机会了
Don't you see? This is it. This is our big chance.
就像Otis说的…
It's like what Otis says,
当机会来临时…
when it comes, you got to grab on
用双手紧紧抓住它
with both hands and hold tight.
那，奶奶怎么办呢，亚里克斯？
Well, what about Granny, Alex?
你说得对，我是很害怕离开这里
You're right. I'm scared of leaving here.
你为什么就不能留下呢？
Why can't you just stay?
玛姬，我必须得走  我要你也跟我走
Maggie, I have to leave, and I want you to come with me.
亚里克斯！快啊！
Alex! Hurry!
我要走了
Well, I got to go.
再见
Bye.
亚里克斯，他们的雷达我们屏蔽不了多久了
Alex, we can't hold off their radar any longer.
好的，来了  我要走了，妈
Yeah, okay. I got to go, Ma.
-再见  多保重  -再见，孩子
Bye. Take it easy. Bye, darling.
后会有期  大家，后会有期了
So long. So long, everybody.
再见，亚里克斯！
Bye, Alex!
再见！
Bye!
再见，亚里克斯！
Bye, Alex. Bye, Alex!
亚里克斯！
Alex!
奶奶…
Granny...
记得要写信告诉我们那边的情况
Be sure and write, or whatever it is they do up there.
亚里克斯！等等，亚里克斯！
Alex! Wait, Alex!
回来！快回来！
Get back! Come on!
再见了！
Bye!
保持距离！注意安全！
Keep your distance! Watch what you're doing.
保持距离！
Keep your distance, now.
这玩意打起仗来真带劲
This baby really packs a punch!
再见
Bye.
看看他啊！再见！
Look at him! Bye!
再见
Bye.
哦，走吧  他们在那儿会很快乐的  再见，亚里克斯！
Oh, go on. They're gonna be happy up there! So long, Alex!
后会有期，亚里克斯！
So long, Alex!
我们就要出名了，对吧，Otis？
We're gonna be famous, aren't we, Otis?
没错！
Yes, sir!
全世界，全宇宙都将知道
The whole world, the whole universe is gonna know about it!
星星闪耀的地方…
Starlite, Starbrite,
就是亚里克斯和玛姬出发去宇宙的地方！
the place where Alex and Maggie left for the stars!
路易斯！路易斯！
Louis! Louis!
你好，星空战士！
Greetings, Starfighter.
你已被星空联盟录取…
You have been recruited by the Star League
誓死保卫边境，抗击约和柯-旦舰队的入侵
to defend the Frontier against Yur and the Ko-Dan Armada.
哇！
Wow!